Inventory of the Ginetta Sagan papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Matchbox, vol. 1, no. 4, 1975 (Box-folder 232: 4)
- Aurora Foundation administrative notes, 1990s (Box-folder 232: 5)
- Biographical file clippings and curricula vitae, 1987-1999 (Box-folder 232: 6-7)
- Correspondence, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 232: 8)
  Includes the Holocaust Memorial Museum
- Italian resistance research, 1943-1990s
  - Office of Strategic Services declassified documents, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 232: 9)
    Photocopies from the National Archives on operational groups in Italy and the OSS intelligence organization in Germany. Includes notes by GS
  - Correspondence and printed matter, 1980s-1990s (Box-folder 232: 10)
    Includes correspondence with Flora Lewis and Elliott Abrams
- Writings by GS on Afghanistan and human rights, 1997 (Box-folder 232: 11-12)
- Forbidden Film Festival, 1984 November 17 (Box-folder 232: 13)
  Includes photographs of GS and Joan Baez at the event in Redwood City
- Human rights clippings, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 232: 14)
- Printed matter by the National Italian American Foundation, 1990s (Box-folder 232: 15)
- Amnesty International, 1997-1999
  - Campaign for Women and Children internal documents, printed matter and clippings, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 233: 1)
  - Ginetta Sagan Fund clippings and correspondence, 1995-1999 (Box-folder 233: 2)
    Includes photographs and negatives from fundraising luncheon
  - Ginetta Sagan Fund award ceremony for Mangala Sharma photographs, 1997 (Box-folder 233: 3)
- François Ponchaud and Torben Retboll correspondence on Cambodia, 1978 (Box-folder 233: 4)
- Printed matter on Asian Americans and human rights in Chile and Greece, 1975-1991 (Box-folder 233: 5)
- Christmas and holiday cards received, 1986-1988 (Box 234)
- Video tapes, 1986-1998
  - "1997 NIAF (National Italian American Foundation) honors Ginetta Sagan" (Box 235)
  - "Consegna della cittadinanza onoraria ai coniugi Sagan, Brusson,", 1997 June 8 (Box 235)
  - "Dark Circle," Independent Documentary Group, 1991 (Box 235)
    Film on nuclear weapons and nuclear power
  - "Ginetta in Poland; Poland human rights conference,", 1998 October (Box 235)
    Duration 33:03. Use copy reference number: 83017_v_0008143
  - "The Ginetta Sagan Fund of Amnesty International,", 1997 January 21 (Box 235)
    Use copy reference number: 83017_v_0008142
    This was made by Amnesty International to promote the Ginetta Sagan Fund. It features Sagan, Joan Baez, and Stockard Channing. Duration 9:35.
  - "Placido Domingo speaks about Barbara Piasecka Johnson,", undated (Box 235)
  - "Stanford Medical School commencement,", 1996 (Box 235)
    Use copy reference number: 83017_v_0008134
    Sagan gives a commencement address at Stanford University's medical school.
  - "World War II: Gruppo Mobile Operativo Giustizia e Libertà,", undated (Box 235)
    Note by GS on box: From Bill Corvo son of Max Corvo, author of The OSS in Italy
  - "Surveillance," by Thomas Claburn, 1990 (Box 235)
  - "1997 SF Opera Gala Celebration and Conversation: Lotfi Mansouri and Michael Krasny" (Box 236)
  - "Amnesty International Human Rights Day Presidential speech,", 1986 December 10 (Box 236)
  - "Brusson/Grappa,", 1994 June (Box 236)
  - "Consegna della cittadinanza onoraria ai coniugi Sagan, Brusson,", 1997 June 8 (Box 236)
  - "Ginetta in Poland; Poland human rights conference,", 1998 October (Box 236)
  - "Lech Wałęsa interview,", 1987 March 21 (Box 236)
  - "Maria Callas special and Czechoslovakia,", undated (Box 236)
  - "Monette, Amnesty International,", 1994 (Box 236)
  - "Nagasaki Journey: The Aftermath of the Bomb,", 1990s (Box 236)
  - "President Václav Havel of Czechoslovakia accepts Ralston Prize from Stanford University School of Law,", 29 September 1994 (Box 236)
    Use copy reference number: 83017_v_0007401
    Includes speeches by various people, including Joan Baez and Havel. Produced by J. Hubbard, and directed by J. Genero; Stanford Instructional Television Network. Duration 50 minutes.
- Condolence cards received on the death of Leonard Sagan, 1998 (Box-folder 237: 1)
- Leonard Sagan letter to Luciano Pavarotti, 1979 September 11 (Box-folder 237: 2)
- Addresses, cards, and notes, 1990s (Box-folder 237: 3-4)
- Video tapes, 1989-1996
  All are on VHS
  - "1997 NIAF Honorees" (Box 238)
  - Amici d'Italia broadcast, 1996 May 26 (Box 238)
  - "Emerging Issues in Human Rights in Southeast Asia: A Conversation with Kritaya Archavanitkul, demographer and activist,", 1996 October 25 (Box 238)
  - "Ginetta, Dana [Rohrabacher], and Karl [Jackson],", 1996 (Box 238)
  - "Ginetta Sagan Tribute,", 1994 October 2 (Box 238)
    Use copy reference number: 83017_v_0008176
    This is an informal recording (a home movie?) documenting a gathering honoring Ginetta Sagan. Guests include Joan Baez. In English. Duration 1:02:12.
  - "Human Rights Conference in Poland,", 1989 (Box 238)
  - "Placido Domingo in Seville,", undated (Box 238)
  - "Presidential Medal of Freedom Award Presentation, White House,", 1996 September 9 (Box 238)
  - "Sherrill Milnes and Placido Domingo in concert,", undated (Box 238)
  - "Sisters and Daughters Betrayed: The Trafficking of Women and Girls and the Fight to End It," Chela Blitt and Global Fund for Women, 1995 (Box 238)
  - "World War II: Gruppo Mobile Operativo Giustizia e Libertà,", undated (Box 238)
    Note by GS on box: "From Bill Corvo son of Max Corvo, author of The OSS in Italy"
- Sound recordings, undated
  On compact sound cassette
  - "Ginetta Sagan on Vietnam" (Box 238)
  - "Church Music" (Box 238)
- Video tapes, 1981, 1996-1999
  - "1997 Living Legacy Awards" (Box 239)
  - "1997 NIAF Honors Ginetta Sagan" (Box 239)
  - "Afghanistan: A Plan for Peace," Foundation of Hope, 1999 April (Box 239)
  - "The Annihilation of Jews Living in Bransk, Poland, During the Holocaust and Ongoing Anti-Semitism," Frontline, 1996 April 17 (Box 239)
  - "Giancarlo Masini Interviews Ginetta Sagan,", undated (Box 239)
  - "The Political Life of Pope John Paul II," FrontLine, 1999 October (Box 239)
  - "Sky at Westminster Abbey: Commemorating 20 Years of Amnesty International,", 1981 February 24 (Box 239)
- Amnesty International, 1993-1997
  - Correspondence, mainly internal, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 240: 1)
    Includes GS letter to Leon Panetta
  - Ginetta Sagan Fund correspondence, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 240: 2-3)
  - Newsletters and reports, 1997 (Box-folder 240: 4)
- Biographical clippings, 1974-1998 (Box-folder 240: 5-6)
- Calendars, 1982, 1992 (Box-folder 240: 7)
- Personal correspondence (Laurene and Steve Jobs, Dana Rohrabacher, John Shattuck, Flora Lewis, and Zbigniew Romaszewski), 1996-1999 (Box-folder 240: 8)
- Photographs of GS with Leonard Sagan, Joan Baez, and others, 1997 (Box-folder 240: 9)
- Research materials on Nazi war criminals and South Africa, 1975-1993 (Box-folder 240: 10-11)
- Writings by GS, 1987, 1997
  - "Silence is Complicity" speech and notes, 1997 (Box-folder 240: 12)
  - GS notes on Vietnam and Washington, 1987 (Box-folder 240: 13)
- Gli ultimi tempi di un regime, by Ildefonso Schuster, photocopy, 1960 (Box-folder 240: 14)
- Human rights clippings, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 240: 15)
- Amnesty International internal documents and clippings, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 241: 1)
- Vietnam research materials, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 241: 2-3)
  Includes photographs of GS and Joan Baez
- Invitations received and addresses, 1990s (Box-folder 241: 4)
- Photographs, 1950s-1988
  - GS in Italy, Poland, and an unidentified commencement ceremony, 1980s (Box-folder 241: 5)
  - GS with family, probably in Italy, 1980s (Box-folder 241: 6)
    Negatives
  - Sting and GS, 1988 (Box-folder 241: 7)
  - GS and her sons, 1950s or 1960s (Box-folder 241: 8)
- Calendars, 1987, 1991, 1995 (Box-folder 241: 9)
- Amnesty International, 1976-1998
  - Internal documents, correspondence, clippings, and printed matter, 1976-1997 (Box-folder 242: 1-3)
  - Notes and address lists, 1987 (Box-folder 242: 4)
  - Ginetta Sagan Fund appeals, 1995 (Box-folder 242: 5)
  - Czechoslovakia, 1988 (Box-folder 242: 6)
  - Refugees in the Middle East, 1998 (Box-folder 242: 7)
- Map of reeducation camps and prisons in the Socialist Republic of Vietnam, 1989 (Box-folder 242: 8)
- Humanitas drafts and notes on boat people, circa 1980 (Box-folder 242: 9)
- Photographs of GS with Lidia Ghielmetti, Joan Baez, Leonard Sagan, and others, 1990s (Box-folder 242: 10-11)
- Italian resistance research materials, 1998 (Box-folder 242: 12)
- Stanford medical school commencement address, by GS, 1996 (Box-folder 242: 13)
- Wall calendars, 1988, 1990 (Box-folder 242: 14-15)
- Human rights clippings, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 242: 16)
- Amnesty International, 1967-1997
  - Correspondence, 1981-1997 (Box-folder 243: 1)
  - Development operational plan, 1995 (Box-folder 243: 2)
  - Donor lists and thank you cards, 1984-1999 (Box-folder 243: 3)
  - Ginetta Sagan Fund correspondence, press releases, and printed matter, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 243: 4)
  - Group 19 ledgers, 1980, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 243: 5)
  - Letters sent (Mai Van Bo, Ronald Reagan, and Gloria Lane), 1967-1991 (Box-folder 243: 6)
    Includes clippings on GS
  - "Memorandum to the International Conference on Vietnam and Indochina, 1973 February 9 (Box-folder 243: 7)
- Aurora Foundation correspondence, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 243: 8-9)
- Biographical clippings, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 243: 10)
- Personal letters received, 1978-1997 (Box-folder 243: 11-12)
- Human rights clippings and collected, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 243: 13-14)
- Address book, 1977 (Box-folder 244: 1)
- Amnesty International, 1973-1999
  - Administrative records, 1988-1999
    - Board of Directors meetings agendas and reports, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 244: 2-3)
    - Ginetta Sagan Fund correspondence and printed matter, 1988-1999 (Box-folder 244: 4)
  - Subject files, 1973-1998
    - Afghanistan, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 244: 5)
    - Chile, 1973-1988 (Box-folder 244: 6)
    - Czechoslovakia, 1978-1990 (Box-folder 244: 7)
    - Georgia, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 244: 8)
    - Poland, 1982-1998 (Box-folder 244: 9-12)
      Includes list of Polish prisoners of conscience in 1985
    - South Africa, 1994-1998 (Box-folder 244: 13-14)
    - Bosnia subject file, 1993-1999 (Box-folder 245: 1)
  - Communications audit, 1998 September (Box-folder 245: 2)
  - Ginetta Sagan Fund correspondence and printed matter, 1994-1998 (Box-folder 245: 3-5)
  - Internal documents, correspondence and printed matter, 1992-1999 (Box-folder 245: 6)
- Italian resistance research materials, 1941, undated (Box-folder 245: 7)
  Photocopies from OSS records at the National Archives. Includes Luigi Barzini letter to Gaetano Polverelli and report on Italian border police
- GS notes written while visiting Mauthausen, circa 1977 (Box-folder 245: 8)
- Personal correspondence and clippings, 1992, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 245: 9)
  Includes letter from Joan Baez
- Photographs of unidentified concentration camps, reprints, circa 1945 (Box-folder 245: 10)
  Probably Mauthausen
- Human rights and World War II clippings, mainly in Italian, 1992 (Box-folder 245: 11)
- Amnesty International, 1971-1996
  - Greece file, 1971-1990 (Box-folder 246: 1)
  - Internal correspondence (Jack Healey and Winston Nagan) and printed matter, 1975-1996 (Box-folder 246: 2-3)
- Aurora Foundation press releases on Zbigniew Romaszewski award, 1987 (Box-folder 246: 4)
- Biographical file, 1977-1996 (Box-folder 246: 5-6)
  Includes clippings and a photocopy of the Presidential Medal of Freedom certificate
- Personal correspondence (Barbara Piasecka Johnson, Michael Rhodes Films, and others), 1991-2000 (Box-folder 246: 7-8)
- Per non dimenticare, by Stefania Pasini, 1990s (Box-folder 246: 9)
  Textbook on the Holocaust in Italian
- Research materials on Nazi war criminals, 1963-1992 (Box-folder 246: 10)
- Leonard Sagan writing on trip to Italy, 1995 (Box-folder 246: 11)
- Aurora Foundation, 1981-2000
  - Financial records, 1982-2000 (Box-folder 247: 1-3)
  - Meeting minutes and notes, 1995 (Box-folder 247: 4-6)
  - Board of Directors correspondence, 1986-2000 (Box-folder 247: 7-8)
  - Meeting minutes, 1981-1989 (Box-folder 248: 1-2)
  - Notes on Foundation assets, drafts, and correspondence, 1991 (Box-folder 248: 3-7)
  - Vietnam research material, 1987-1993 (Box-folder 248: 8)
- Video tapes, 1985-1999
  - "40th Anniversary of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights,", 1988 (Box 249)
  - "Afghanistan: A Plan for Peace," Foundation of Hope, 1999 April (Box 249)
  - "Consegna della cittadinanza onoraria ai coniugi Sagan, Brusson,", 1997 June 8 (Box 249)
  - "First Annual Ginetta Sagan Award, Villa Firenze, Washington, D.C.,", 1997 May 14 (Box 249)
    Use copy reference number: 83017_v_0008136
    The presentation of this award to Mangala Sharma occurred at Villa Firenze in Washington, D.C. Duration 1:06:00.
  - "Ginetta Sagan, Belva Davis, Bay Area Close Up,", undated (Box 249)
  - "Ginetta Sagan Presidential Medal of Freedom award,", 1996 (Box 249)
    Use copy reference number: 83017_v_0007600
    Channel C-SPAN2 coverage of Ginetta Sagan being presented the Presidential Medal of Freedom from President Bill Clinton. In English. Duration 15:26.
  - "Ginetta Sagan Tribute,", 1994 October 4 (Box 249)
  - "Interview with an Executioner: A Documentary,", undated (Box 249)
  - "Lech Wałęsa and Joan Baez, Aurora Foundation, Poland,", 1985 November (Box 249)
  - "Lech Wałęsa Interview, Poland, 11:02 version,", 1987 (Box 249)
  - "Lech Wałęsa Interview, Poland, 21 minute version,", 1987 March 27 (Box 249)
  - "Lech Wałęsa Interview, in Polish, no translation,", undated (Box 249)
  - "The Ginetta Sagan Fund of Amnesty International, 9:35" (Box 250)
  - "Ginetta Sagan interview with Vincent Trèves,", undated (Box 250)
  - "Ginetta Sagan's interview with Lidia Ghielmetti,", 1994 June 16-17 (Box 250)
    Video drop out near the end of the tape. Use copy reference number: 83017_v_0007588. Duration 1:28:09.
  - "Poland, Joan Baez, and Lech Wałęsa, 11:30,", 1985 November (Box 250)
  - "Poland, November, 1985, Michael Rhodes Films" (Box 250)
  - Primo Levi: The Memory of the Offence, by Denys Blakeway, BBC, 1992 (Box 250)
  - "World War II: Gruppo Mobile Operativo Giustizia e Libertà, 10 minutes,", undated (Box 250)
- Sound recordings, 1973, 1989
  - The Book: On the Taboo Against Knowing Who You Are, by Alan Watts, undated (Box 250)
  - "Conclusions by Jim Gilroy. Notes by Joseph Sackney,", undated (Box 250)
  - "Conversations,", 1989 March 21 (Box 250)
  - "David Hathaway, New York City,", 1973 September 30 (Box 250)
  - "Joan Baez in Milan,", undated (Box 250)
    2 cassettes
  - "Joan Baez in Spanish,", undated (Box 250)
  - "John Shattuck at Stanford,", undated (Box 250)
  - "Opera,", undated (Box 250)
  - "Roberto Devereaux,", undated (Box 250)
  - "Tape of inspirational readings for Cosette Thompson,", undated (Box 250)
- Video tapes, 1985-1997
  On VHS unless otherwise indicated
  - "1997 NIAF honors Ginetta Sagan, 4 minutes" (Box 251)
  - "Alongside Nelson Mandela: Reminiscences of a Former Political Prisoner Under Apartheid. A Conversation with Ahmed Kathrada, 62 minutes,", 1996 November 8 (Box 251)
  - "Amnesty International General Conference,", 1992 (Box 251)
  - "Bay Area Close-Up on Ginetta Sagan, KRON TV/Belva Davis,", 1995 April 24 (Box 251)
  - "Commencement, edited,", undated (Box 251)
  - "Ginetta on Today Show,", undated (Box 251)
  - "Ginetta Sagan address,", 1994 March 17 (Box 251)
    Use copy reference number: 83017_v_0008135
    Sagan address to, presumably, Amnesty International filmed in Italy. Duration 13:53.
  - "Ginetta Sagan on Cambodia,", undated (Box 251)
  - "Kolaps, G.A.P.: Croatia,", undated (Box 251)
  - "Human Rights with Ginetta Sagan, Karl Jackson and Dana Rohrabacher,", 1996 February 15 (Box 251)
  - "Living Legacy Awards,", 1994 (Box 252)
    Presentation of award to Barbara Piasecka Johnson by Ginetta Sagan and Patricia Neal
  - "Amnesty International: Eleanor Roosevelt,", undated (Box 252)
  - "Amnesty International: Indonesia Campaign 1994, Human Rights Violations in East Timor,", undated (Box 252)
  - "Amnesty International: Turkey,", 1995 (Box 252)
  - A Debt to Honor, documentary on individuals who rescued Italian Jews after 1943, 1995 (Box 252)
  - "Lech Wałęsa and Joan Baez, 1.5 hours, unedited version,", 1985 (Box 252)
  - "Lech Wałęsa interview, 21 minute version,", 1987 March 21 (Box 252)
  - "Living Legacy Awards, Ginetta Sagan,", 1992 (Box 252)
  - "Opus Sacrum for Human Rights award introduction, Barbara Piasecka Johnson,", undated (Box 252)
  - "Poland,", 1985 November (Box 252)
  - "Women in the Resistance in World War II and after," lecture by GS at the Institute for Research on Women and Gender, Stanford University, 1995 October 2 (Box 252)
  - "Abolish the IRS with Steve Forbes,", 1996 July 15 (Box 253)
  - "Amnesty International, Colombia: Getting Away with Murder,", 1994 March (Box 253)
  - "Amnesty International, Human Rights Day Presidential Speech,", 1986 December 10 (Box 253)
  - "Annual report,", 1992 (Box 253)
  - "Domingo, Seville,", undated (Box 253)
  - "Ginetta Sagan Interviews,", undated (Box 253)
    Use copy reference number: 83017_v_0007596
    Italian journalist interviewing Ginetta Sagan; Channel 4 Bay Area Close-Up segment by Belva Davis on Sagan starting her foundation; "The Ginetta Sagan Fun: Amnesty International" short promotional film for Amnesty International about the organization and Ginetta Sagan with photo and video montage, along with testimonials from Ginetta Sagan, Joan Baez, and Stockard Channing. In Italian and English. Duration 26:07.
  - "Ginetta Sagan in Italian" (Ginetta Sagan and Tiziana's father), 1994 June 11 (Box 253)
    Use copy reference number: 83017_v_0007601
    In Italian. Duration 1:08:35.
  - "Jerzy Kluger interview," Today Show, 1996 April (Box 253)
  - Non abbiate paura: Storia di un Papa, 1996 (Box 253)
  - Sisters and Daughters Betrayed: The Sex Trade of Women and Girls: An International Conference on the Dynamics of Sexual Coercion, 1996 (Box 253)
  - "Tito's Legacy," BBC TV, 1992 (Box 253)
  - Turkey: Trading with Torture, Amnesty International USA, 1989 February 14 (Box 253)
  - "Aurora Foundation,", 1985 November (Box 254)
    UCA-30 extended play videocassette
  - "Joan Baez sings for Lech Wałęsa, Poland,", 1985 (Box 254)
- Ginetta Sagan: A Culinary Biography, by Leonard and Ginetta Sagan, 1994 (Box 254)
- Violations of Human Rights in the Socialist Republic of Vietnam, 1983, 1989 (Box 254)
- Aurora Foundation, 1982-1990
  - Activities, 1989 (Box-folder 255: 1)
  - Anchorage Foundation correspondence, 1989 (Box-folder 255: 2)
  - Board of Directors meetings, 1982-1990 (Box-folder 255: 3-10)
  - Aurora Foundation Vietnam report clippings, 1987 (Box-folder 255: 11)
  - Festival of Forbidden Film, 1984 November (Box-folder 255: 12)
  - General correspondence, 1988 January-February (Box-folder 255: 13)
  - Poland trip report, 1985 December 9 (Box-folder 255: 14)
    GS describes meeting with Joan Baez and Lech Wałęsa in Poland
  - Romaszewski award ceremony file, 1987 December 10 (Box-folder 255: 15-18)
    Includes photographs
  - Sadowski, Christine, correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 255: 19)
    Includes photographs of Solidarity posters and Sadowski with Lech Wałęsa
  - Financial records, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 255: 20)
  - Vuillerminaz, Aurora, undated (Box-folder 255: 21)
- Awards, 1987-1992
  - Jefferson Awards, 1987 (Box-folder 255: 22)
    Includes photograph of GS
  - Women's International Center Living Legacy Awards, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 255: 23)
    Includes photographs of GS and Barbara Piasecka Johnson
- Amnesty International, 1996, 2000
  - Bambini di Guerra exhibit, 1996 (Box-folder 256: 1)
  - Kosovo file, 2000 (Box-folder 256: 2)
- Aurora Foundation, 1991-2000
  - Activities, 1999 (Box-folder 256: 3)
  - Board meetings, 1991-2000 (Box-folder 256: 4)
  - East Timor, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 256: 5-6)
  - Paris trip report, 1992 October 2 (Box-folder 256: 7)
  - Polish human rights conference, 1998 (Box-folder 256: 8-9)
    Includes photograph of GS at conference
- Biographical file, 1974-2000
  - Clippings, 1974-2000 (Box-folder 256: 10)
  - National Italian American Foundation award, 1997 (Box-folder 256: 11)
  - Presidential Medal of Freedom ceremony, 1997 (Box-folder 256: 12)
    Includes program and photographs of GS with Joan Baez and Bill and Hillary Clinton
  - Curriculum vitae, 1998 (Box-folder 256: 13)
- Michael Rhodes Films correspondence, 1994 (Box-folder 256: 14)
- Writings by GS, 1994, 1996
  - "The Guilty, the Brave, and the Indifferent," Stanford Medical School commencement address, 1996 June 16 (Box-folder 256: 15)
  - "Introduction to Barbara Piasecka Johnson,", 1994 March (Box-folder 256: 16)
- Aurora Foundation, 2002-2006
  - Minutes of Special Board Meeting, 2002 January 24 (Box-folder 257: 1)
    Includes related correspondence, address lists and receipts
  - Financial records, 2004-2006 (Box-folder 257: 2)
- Biographical file, 1968-2000
  - Award and pension certificate from the Italian government, 1968, 1995, 1999 (Box-folder 257: 3)
    Includes photocopies of La Croce al Merito di Guerra and Grande Ufficiale Ordine al Merito della Repubblica Italiana
  - Obituaries and death announcement cards for GS, 2000 (Box-folder 257: 4)
  - Joan Baez poem for GS, 1993 January 30 (Box-folder 257: 5)
- Photographs, 1940s-2000
  - Portraits with family and friends, 1940s-1960s (Box-folder 257: 6)
  - Amnesty International event, 1990s (Box-folder 257: 7)
  - GS with Lidia Ghielmetti, negatives, and proofsheet, 1990s (Box-folder 257: 8)
  - GS at Italian American Museum, 1998 June 19 (Box-folder 257: 9)
  - GS with Václav Havel, skiing in Italy, at AI events, with Joan Baez and others, 1950-1994 (Box-folder 257: 10)
  - GS at Living Legacy Awards with Barbara Piasecka Johnson, 1990s (Box-folder 257: 11)
  - 50th anniversary of GS's liberation, 1995 (Box-folder 257: 12)
  - GS at the Presidential Medial of Freedom, with Joan Baez, Nancy Pelosi, and others, 1980s-1990s (Box-folder 257: 13)
  - GS in Poland with Joan Baez, Lech Wałęsa, Henryk Jankowski, and others, 1985 (Box-folder 257: 14-16)
  - GS with friends, 2000 (Box-folder 257: 17)
  - GS cooking for a Washington Post story, 1966 November (Box-folder 257: 18)
- GS commencement speech at Starr King School for the Ministry, 1981 (Box-folder 257: 19)
- After the Spring Came Winter, by Karel and Ivan Kyncl, 1985 (Box-folder 257: 20)
  Signed by the authors
- Amnesty International donor list for the Ginetta Sagan Fund, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 258: 1)
- Aurora Foundation, 1983-2003
  - Board of Directors meeting agendas, minutes, and reports, 1994-1995, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 258: 2-3)
    Relates mainly to a GS biography project
  - Correspondence, 1995-2003 (Box-folder 258: 4-5)
    Relates mainly to Sim Smiley's book on GS
  - Notes on Linda Holtz and travel expenses to Poland, 1987 (Box-folder 258: 6)
  - Letterhead and envelopes, 1990s (Box-folder 258: 7)
  - Outline by Sim Smiley for a book on Ginetta Sagan's life, 2000 June 1 (Box-folder 258: 8)
    Includes related correspondence and photocopy of GS's application for immigration, 1952 May 20
  - Poland files, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 258: 9)
    Includes memoranda by Christine Sadowski on meetings with Solidarity members in Poland
  - Report to the Board of Directors of the Aurora Foundation on writing a biography of GS, by Sim Smiley, 2001 December 10 (Box-folder 258: 10)
  - Violations of Human Rights in the Socialist Republic of Vietnam, drafts and printed copies, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 258: 11-12)
  - Organization tax returns, 1999-2002 (Box-folder 258: 13)
- Biographical file, 1994, 2000
  - GS interview by Mary Peace Finley, 1994 November (Box-folder 258: 14)
  - Will, 2000 March 7 (Box-folder 258: 15)